{
    "section": "Wake Turbulence",
    "section_number": "7",
    "questions": [
        {
            "index": "01",
            "question": "Avoiding wake turbulence is",
            "answers": {
                "1": "the sole responsibility of ATC.",
                "2": "the responsibility of the pilot, only when advised by ATC of the possibility of wake turbulence.",
                "3": "a responsibility shared by both the pilot and ATC.",
                "4": "the sole responsibility of the pilot."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "4",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence / Considerations"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "02",
            "question": "Hazardous wake turbulence caused by aircraft in still air",
            "answers": {
                "1": "dissipates immediately.",
                "2": "dissipates rapidly.",
                "3": "may persist for 5 minutes or more.",
                "4": "persists indefinitely."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "3",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "03",
            "question": "Which response is most correct with respect to wake turbulence?",
            "answers": {
                "1": "Wing tip vortices are carried by the ambient wind.",
                "2": "Wing tip vortices have a circular and downward motion.",
                "3": "Wake turbulence exists behind all aeroplanes and helicopters in flight.",
                "4": "All of the above are correct."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "4",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence",
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence / Vortex Characteristics / General"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "04",
            "question": "The wing tip vortices generated by a heavy aeroplane can cause a lighter aircraft encountering them to",
            "answers": {
                "1": "go out of control.",
                "2": "continue descent even when maximum power is applied.",
                "3": "sustain structural damage.",
                "4": "experience any of the above situations."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "4",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence",
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence / Vortex Characteristics / General"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "05",
            "question": "During the two minutes after the passage of a heavy aeroplane in cruising flight, hazardous wing tip vortices will",
            "answers": {
                "1": "dissipate completely.",
                "2": "dissipate rapidly.",
                "3": "dissipate very slowly.",
                "4": "remain at cruising altitude."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "3",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "06",
            "question": "The pilot of a light aircraft on final approach close behind a heavier aircraft should plan the approach to land",
            "answers": {
                "1": "beyond the touchdown point of the other aircraft.",
                "2": "prior to the touchdown point of the other aircraft.",
                "3": "at the touchdown point of the other aircraft.",
                "4": "to the right or left of the touchdown point of the other aircraft."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "1",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence / Considerations"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "07",
            "question": "With regard to a flight itinerary, the responsible person means someone who",
            "answers": {
                "1": "has agreed to report the aircraft overdue.",
                "2": "is 18 years of age or over.",
                "3": "holds an aeronautical license.",
                "4": "has agreed to report the arrival of the aircraft."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "1",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence / Considerations"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "08",
            "question": "Wake turbulence is produced by",
            "answers": {
                "1": "heavy aeroplanes only, regardless of their speed.",
                "2": "turbo-jet powered aircraft only.",
                "3": "fast moving aeroplanes only, regardless of their weight.",
                "4": "all fixed and rotary wing aircraft."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "4",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "09",
            "question": "Wake turbulence caused by a departing large aeroplane begins",
            "answers": {
                "1": "before rotation.",
                "2": "with rotation.",
                "3": "after becoming airborne.",
                "4": "with full power application."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "2",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence / Vortex Characteristics"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "10",
            "question": "Wake turbulence caused by a departing aeroplane is most severe immediately",
            "answers": {
                "1": "before rotation.",
                "2": "following take-off.",
                "3": "above its flight path.",
                "4": "following full power application."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "2",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "11",
            "question": "Which statement concerning wing tip vortices is false?",
            "answers": {
                "1": "Vortices normally settle below and behind the aircraft.",
                "2": "With a light cross-wind, one vortex can remain stationary over the ground for some time.",
                "3": "Lateral movement of vortices, even in a no wind condition, may place a vortex core over a parallel runway.",
                "4": "Vortices are caused directly by ‘jet wash’."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "4",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence / Vortex Characteristics / General"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "12",
            "question": "Wake turbulence will be greatest when generated by an aeroplane which is",
            "answers": {
                "1": "heavy, landing configuration and slow speed.",
                "2": "heavy, clean configuration and slow speed.",
                "3": "light, clean configuration and high speed.",
                "4": "heavy, take-off configuration and slow speed."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "2",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "13",
            "question": "A helicopter in forward flight produces hazardous vortices",
            "answers": {
                "1": "which rise above the helicopter.",
                "2": "similar to wing tip vortices.",
                "3": "which remains at the same level as the helicopter.",
                "4": "ahead of the helicopter."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "2",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "14",
            "question": "Which statement concerning vortices caused by helicopters is correct?",
            "answers": {
                "1": "Helicopter vortices are generally weak and dissipate rapidly",
                "2": "The size of the helicopter has little bearing on the intensity of the vortices.",
                "3": "Helicopter vortices are less intense than the vortices of an aeroplane of the same weight.",
                "4": "Wind does not influence the movement of vortices generated by a helicopter in hovering flight."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "2",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "15",
            "question": "What effect would a light cross-wind have on the wing tip vortices generated by a large aeroplane that had just taken off? A light cross-wind",
            "answers": {
                "1": "could cause one vortex to remain over the runway for some time.",
                "2": "would rapidly dissipate the strength of both vortices.",
                "3": "would rapidly clear the runway of all vortices.",
                "4": "would not affect the lateral movement of the vortices."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "1",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-AIR - Wake Turbulence / Vortex Characteristics / General"
            ]
        }
    ]
}